## **KEVIN LONG**

Austin, TX

Phone: 512-975-0082 | Email: kevinjlong75@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/klong75 | GitHub: https://www.github.com/KLong75 |

Portfolio: https://www.klong75.github.io/KLong\_Portfolio/

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer. Graduated from the full stack web development program at the University of Texas in July of 2022. Currently seeking full time employment in web development. Bachelor of arts in theater and pursued a career in puppetry for several years. At first glance coding may seem quite different from puppetry, however both are highly collaborative creative processes that revolve around creative problem solving in an effort to reach a common goal. Both endeavors require a focused group of people working together to build something. The tools and building materials just happen to be different. Thrive on creative problem solving and collaboration. Excited to continue my coding journey. Coding is not only a path to gainful and meaningful employment but also a way to further personal creative pursuits and make positive contributions to both the local and global communities.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+, SQL

**Applications:** GitHub, MongoDB, Mongoose, Sequelize, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, Google, Material UI

#### **P**ROJECTS

MUSICOLOGY | https://github.com/KLong75/musician-networking-app | https://musicology-umekev.herokuapp.com/

- A MERN stack networking application for musicians.
- Role: Primary author and project manager
- Tools: MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, bcrypt, JSON web tokens,

### Who Do? | github.com/truppeiner/who-do | who-do-austin.herokuapp.com/login

- A full stack social media type application that allows users to create and share events in the Austin area,
- Role: Backend database and data models | Frontend: Javascript
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js, Bootstrap

### Movies R Us | github.com/KLong75/Movies-R-Us-KJ | klong75.github.io/Movies-R-Us-KJ/

- Allows users to browse titles by genre across all major subscription streaming services and link directly to a selected title on any streaming service that carries the title.
- I wrote the vast majority of the Javascript for the application.
- HTML, Javascript, CSS

#### EXPERIENCE

## First and Second Grade Teacher Austin Discovery School

8/2020 - 8/2021 Austin, TX

Utilized clear communication and critical thinking skills to develop and implement lesson plans for all subjects across two grade levels. Responsible for safety and supervision of my class. Teaching takes flexibility, adaptability, patience, multi-tasking, quick thickening, and a thick skin.

Key Accomplishment

• Successfully developed and implemented an innovative online learning system for virtual learning during COVID. This experience led directly to my interest in coding.

### Preschool Teacher Children's Discovery Center

7/2019 - 6/2020

**Austin, TX** 

Supervision, care, and safety of a classroom of 2 year old children. Such work takes flexibility, adaptability, patience, multi-tasking, quick thickening, and a thick skin.

Manufacturer 8/2018 - 7/2019
Calton Cases Austin, TX

Fabrication and installation by hand of interiors for custom guitar, bass, banjo, mandolin, and violin cases using foam, fabric, and a variety of glues. We tracked progress on orders using a Kanban board similar in fashion to those used by coding teams.

## Procurement Supervisor University of TX, Athletics Nutrition Center

10/2017 - 8/2018

Austin, TX

inventory management, ordering of all food and supplies, receiving orders, supervising stocking of all items received, researching new items, communicating with vendors, supervising monthly physical inventory, customer service, etc.

Key Accomplishment

implemented and developed an electronic ordering and inventory system

## Project Administrator Dodge Moving and Storage

1/2017 - 10/2017

Earth City, MO

inventory management, account management, invoicing, data entry, writing and researching contracts, logistical planning, cost analysis, bill collection, communicating with warehouse, dispatch, and drivers, customer service, etc.

Dairy Manager 6/2016 - 10/2016
Natural Grocers Austin, TX

placed orders for goods to be sold in the refrigerated and frozen departments, inventory control, product selection, communicated with vendors and sales reps, received and stocked orders, deposited cash at closing, store key holder, cashiering, customer service, etc.

Freelance Theater Artist Self Employed

12/2015 - 6/2016

**Austin, TX** 

performed a variety of various responsibilities depending on the project

## Grocery Order Clerk Wheatsville Food Co-op

8/2013 - 12/2015 Austin, TX

placed orders for goods to be sold in the packaged grocery department, inventory control, supervised and trained stocking clerks, maintained purchase log, received deliveries, stocked shelves, customer service, etc.

Key Accomplishment

 developed and implemented system for receiving and stocking orders to increase efficiency and reduce shrink

### Frozen Buyer Linden Hills Food Co-op

6/2004 - 8/2013 Minneapolis, MN

inventory control, ordered products to be sold, negotiated sale deals with vendors, built displays, trained new stocking clerks, researched new products, received orders, stocked shelves, customer service, etc.

Key Accomplishment

- utilized P.O.S. system to keep a perpetual inventory of the frozen department
- utilized the perpetual inventory to automatically generate purchase orders based on frequency of sales and the current on hand inventory

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of Texas**

Austin, TX

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Full Stack Web Development

Bachelor of Arts in Theater Truman State University

Kirksville, MO